Finding Aid for Wilfred B. Shaw pamphlets and reprints, 1935-1936
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wilfred B. Shaw pamphlets and reprints 1935-1936
Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959
1 box
[746] DA 2; S537; P186
Director of the University of Michigan alumni association, includes articles on alumni affairs and university history.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was assembled for several sources.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Wilfred B. Shaw was born January 10, 1880 in Adrian, Michigan. After graduating from the University of Michigan in 1904, Shaw was named general secretary of the Alumni Association and editor of the Michigan Alumnus. He served in this capacity until 1929 when he was appointed director of alumni relations, a position that had been established by the Regents for continuing education and other services to graduates. He retired from this position in 1951. In 1934, Shaw founded and served as first editor of the Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review.
Before coming to the University to head up its alumni relations program, Shaw had attended the Art School at Chicago. Shaw achieved some renown as an artist and etcher, particularly of U-M campus scenes, buildings, and personalities. He had many exhibitions of his work and his illustrations were used in the University's alumni publications and in his various other writings.
Shaw died May 28, 1959.
The Shaw pamphlet collection consists of articles and reprints about University of Michigan alumni affairs and several on oriental art.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan--History
- Pamphlets and reprints
  - The problem of the alumni, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Alumni and adult education, 1929
  - Alumni education-present programs, 1930 (2 copies)
  - Athletics and alumni education, 1931
  - A bibliography of the University of Michigan, 1936
  - Continuing education for the college graduate, 1930
  - Educating the alumni, 1929
  - Illustration and the newspaper, l904
  - Intellectual needs of alumni, 1932
  - A new power in University affairs, 1922
  - Principles of alumni office organization, 1927
  - The relation of modern American art to that of China and Japan, 1910
  - Religion and nature in oriental art, 1916
  - Rossetti and Botticelli: a comparison of ideals and art, 1905
  - A service that serves, 1934